MIKOTO ELEMENTARY
All right, good morning.
Okay, take your seats.
It's Monday.
Looks like Kayo's late again.
What's wrong, Satoru?
Take your seat.
All right, I'm taking attendance.
-Tokiko Asano.
-Here.
-Yuji Arakawa.
-Yukari Ishizaki.
-Here.
-Yuuki Ueda.
-Mako Ono.
-Here.
-Sachiko Onodera.
-Manami Kumagai.
-Here.
Is this a Revival?
-Tsutomu Sakai.
-Here.
This is 18 years ago.
-Hiromi Sugita.
-Here.
FIFTH GRADE, CLASS 4
FUTURE
FEBRUARY 15TH CLASS ATTENDANTS:
KENYA KOBAYASHI MANAMI KUMAGAI
What am I supposed to do?
Why would a Revival
take me back this far?
Wait. That reminds me.
What about Mom?
Satoru.
What's up?
Nurse's office.
My head is hurting a little.
Mom! Mom!
Mom!
Mom.
Did I wake you?
Hamburger or meatballs?
Which do you want?
Hamburger.
Okay.
This is happiness.
It's really good.
This morning... we got in a big fight
because you couldn't find your flute.
And now it's like you don't remember.
I'm...
Sorry.
You don't have to cry about it!
Mom.
It's really good. Thank you.
What's gotten into you?
It's nothing.
The simple times.
That came and went.
The time I lost.
No way...
will I lose these moments this time.
Does this mean starting over
from 18 years ago
is the way to save Mom?
But why?
Oh, right.
This is before Kayo Hinazuki
is kidnapped and murdered.
Which means since this angle
is 70 degrees...
FEBRUARY 16TH
TUESDAY
...you take 180 degrees minus 70 degrees
which equals 110 degrees.
Now that leaves these two angles.
Since this is an isosceles triangle,
what should we do?
Does this Revival mean
I'm supposed to prevent her murder?
-I think you should divide it by two.
-Good. Correct.
But...
I mostly don't know anything about
Kayo Hinazuki.
Not even the exact date of the crime.
Fifty-five degrees.
And that is how you find the angles
of an isosceles triangle.
Now, this is definitely going to be
on the test.
-Those bruises...
-So, practice them.
-Wait, could it be...?
-How about we try solving question five.
By the way, Satoru...
do you like Hinazuki or something?
You were staring at her all period.
-Really?
-So, that's the deal?
All right, leave it to me.
I can help you talk to Hinazuki!
Hold on a second. Look...
That's right, Hiromi gets taken
after Hinazuki...
HIROMI SUGITA (11)
KAYO HINAZUKI (10)
-So, what is it, then?
-What is it?
All right. I made up my mind.
I'll take this case on.
I don't know if I like her,
but she's been on my mind.
That means that you like her!
-No!
-It means you like her!
-Stop saying it!
-I'll hook you up! We're counting on you!
You stupid?
That's the first thing you say?
Oh, I said that aloud...
Look.
I was wondering if we could be friends.
What exactly about me
made you to say this?
That's...
But... I guess I kind of get it.
You know.
Because you're fake like me.
I saw you running home yesterday.
Is your mother really that important?
Yeah.
I see.
Wait, hold on, I wasn't done!
I want to be friends with you.
Friends?
Then... can you murder
someone for me?
Satoru. How did it go?
Yeah. I feel like I got her to open up
to me just a little bit.
I see.
Satoru...
I think what you're doing with Hinazuki
is really important for some reason.
I'm sure everyone would want to help you.
So, you can come to me with anything.
Okay. Thanks, Kenya.
By the way, Satoru,
have you read through the essays?
They're really interesting.
You should read them.
Essays?
"A City Where Only I Am Gone
by Kayo Hinazuki.
When I'm a little older
than I am now,
able to go anywhere I want on my own...
I want to go to some faraway country.
A faraway island."
An island
without any sadness or suffering.
There aren't any adults or children,
classmates,
teachers,
or my mother on the island.
On the island,
I climb trees when I want to
swim in the ocean when I want to
and sleep when I want to.
This essay is without a doubt
a cry for help from Kayo Hinazuki.
Hinazuki.
What are you doing here?
That's my line.
I said I wanted to be friends.
Fujinuma.
You just pretend, don't you?
You pretend to laugh.
Pretend to be nice.
I can't see your true face.
I think you're right.
I'm just pretending.
I want people to like me.
I want friends.
Not being that good with people,
I thought of what I could do.
So, I decided to try to like other people.
Then pretending became easier to do.
Yeah. Me, too.
As you pretend,
it starts to feel like it is real.
People do all sorts of things
to encourage themselves
to get what they want.
So... I'm going to do
the things I never did.
Hey, Hinazuki.
I'm having a birthday party.
Would you come?
BIRTHDAY INVITATION
You want me to come?
Aren't others going?
I don't know yet.
I wanted you to be the first one
I invited.
It's March 2nd.
You'll come, won't you?
Fujinuma...
aren't your hands cold?
Oh, guess I left my gloves somewhere.
Looks like my hand's a little bigger.
You stupid?
But...
you're a little easier
to talk to right now.
Yeah. Well, I decided
I wouldn't lie to you.
Bye! See you tomorrow!
This is the last place
Hinazuki was ever seen.
So, when did she go missing?
The first kidnapping was in March.
Wait, everyone should turn 11
in fifth grade.
KAYO HINAZUKI (10)
That's it.
Hinazuki's birthday must be in March.
And she was killed before her birthday.
Once I know her birthday, I might be able
to narrow down the day she's taken.
Hey, did you guys study?
There's a test today!
-Good morning.
FEBRUARY 20TH
SATURDAY
Did you know?
Totally!
Hey, Hinazuki.
I know this is random,
but when's your birthday?
Hey, everyone!
Fujinuma and Hinazuki
are totally flirting!
-I'm so jealous.
-Must be nice.
I messed up.
I should've picked a better spot.
But I want to find out
as soon as possible.
Excuse me.
Mr. Yashiro.
Oh, what's up, Satoru?
-There's something I'd like to ask.
-All right. What is it?
-Is it about Kayo?
-What?
I've noticed you hanging out lately.
Mr. Yashiro really pays attention.
Yeah.
I wanted to know her birthday.
Birthday? You didn't ask her?
I did... but she wouldn't tell me.
You know, Kayo's very reserved.
I think she really could benefit
from having more friends.
So, I'll do this just this once.
CLASS ATTENDANCE BOOK
Let's see here...
Here you go.
March 2nd.
Same as me?
Now I know when the kidnapping happened.
March 1st.
That's Day X.
The same birthday.
Maybe she felt awkward telling you, then.
-You should just celebrate it with her.
-Yeah.
Satoru, it's all about giving it your all.
Good luck with Kayo.
You can come talk to me anytime.
Thank you, Mr. Yashiro. Bye.
March 1st is ten days away.
There's a high chance the killer
will approach her.
I need to stay by her side
as much as possible.
Hinazuki! You here?!
Hinazuki!
On the deserted island
I think about the city
where only I am gone.
Children go to school
like they always do.
Adults go to work like they always do.
My mother eats like she always does.
Hinazuki!
Don't look...
Close it!
Hinazuki!
What happened, Kayo?
Coming in here by yourself again.
Hurry up and get back to your room.
How did Hinazuki get injured?
Why don't you tell him, Kayo?
I tripped.
Subtitle translation by
Zensho Yamamoto